Guide to the Yale University Art, Architecture, and Art History Theses and Projects
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- "Yale New Haven Arts Forum," and "Issues in Architecture and Culture", Spring 2004; Accession 2004-A-206
  - "Yale New Haven Arts Forum", 2004 (Box 1)
  - "Issues in Architecture and Culture", 2004 (Box 1)
- "re-figuring Williamsburg" presentation booklet, 2004; Accession 2005-A-013
  - "re-figuring Williamsburg," presentation booklet produced by Architecture 905b: Intermediate Planning & Development, 2004 Spring (Box 1)
- Student work of Estelle Margolis (B. Arch, 1955), circa 1952-1955; Accession 2005-A-021
  This accession includes records from Accession 2003-A-077.
  - Residences, 24 March 1952 and undated (Box 1)
  - Town plan perspectives, undated (Box 1)
  - Project for Architecture 21, 20 October 1952 (Folder 2)
  - Projects for Architecture 11, 12, 13, December 1952 (Folder 2)
  - Project for Architecture 21A, January 1953 (Folder 2)
  - Single-span building (Folder 2)
  - Project for Second-year Design, May 1953 (Folder 3)
  - Project for Third-year Design (Folder 4)
  - Bank building (PNB), 25 November 1953 (Box 5)
  - Residence, Undated (Box 5)
  - Small theater, 25 November 1953 (Folder 6)
  - Preliminary proposal for a communication center, 30 November 1954 (Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous sketches and drawings, Undated (Folder 7)
- Year-end exhibit, "Next Wave", 2004; Accession 2005-A-023
  - Undergraduate Posters (24" x 41)
    - Kent Gould, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Ming Thompson, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Elizabeth Bacon, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Zia Tyebjee, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Susanna Chao, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Ross C. Anderson, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Terence Li, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Charles Esteves, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Brendan Muha, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Alexandra Bevan, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Danielle Page, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Jessica Kung, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Erin Gould, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Anya Brickman Raredon, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Gene Cartwright, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Lisa Rothman, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Thomas Kalvik, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Megan Forney, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Gregory Pasquali, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Alanya Schofield, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Garren Givens, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Seher Erdogan, 2004 (Box 1)
    - Brian Stromquist, 2004 (Box 1)
  - 1st and 2nd Year Studio Posters (41" x 89")
    - Course and Faculty, 2004 (Box 1)
    - 502b, spring 2004 -Turner Brooks (Box 1)
    - 502b, spring 2004 -Keith Krumweide (Box 1)
    - 502b, spring 2004 -Amy Lelyveld (Box 1)
    - 502b, spring 2004 -Brian Healy (Box 1)
    - 502b, spring 2004 -Deborah Gans (Box 1)
    - 502b, spring 2004 -Alan Organschi (Box 1)
    - 523a, fall 2003 -Fred Koetter and Ed Mitchell, 2004 (Box 1)
    - 504b, spring 2004 -Ed Mitchell (Box 1)
    - 504b, spring 2004 -Andrea Kahn (Box 1)
    - 503a, fall 2003 -Keith Krumweide, 2004 (Box 1)
    - 503a, fall 2003 -Peter deBretteville, 2004 (Box 1)
    - 503a, fall 2003 -Alec Purves, 2004 (Box 1)
    - 503a, fall 2003 -Alan Organschi, 2004 (Box 1)
    - MED 103 -Eeva-Liisa Pelkonen, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Graduating Graduate Student Posters (41" x 48"), 2004 (Box 2)
    - Abir Ahmad, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Lara Apelian, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Peter Arbour, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Graham Banks, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Robert Berry, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Emily Bidegain, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Erin Carraher, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Marcus Carter, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Christopher Cayten, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Pu Chen, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Stephen Chien, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Joohghyun Cho, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Sandra Choy, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Christopher Dale, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Sarah David, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Katherine Davies, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Gary Eversole, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Patrick Giannini, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Anthony Goldsby, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Zhigang Han, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Katan Hanansen, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Leejung Hong, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Patrick Hyland, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Teresa Jan, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Seyong Jang, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Matthew Jogan, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Daewha Kang, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Meirav Katz, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Malaika Kim, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Youngsun Ko, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Michael Kokora, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Justin Kwok, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Helia Lee, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Spencer Luckey, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Chris Marcinkoski, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Maki Matsubayashi, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Yong Mei, 2004 (Box 2)
    - James Nelson, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Edward Richardson, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Christopher Riordan, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Benjamin Rosenblum, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Sang Wan Seo, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Aaron Smith, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Clinton Smith, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Gregory Sobotka, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Gretchen Stoecker, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Jeffery Stone, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Marissa Sweig, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Thong Tran, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Stephen Van Dyck, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Na Wei, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Kristina Winegar, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Yang Yang, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Kanu Agrawal, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Valerie Casey, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Lihan Hong, 2004 (Box 2)
    - James Nelson, 2004 (Box 2)
    - Adrian Campa, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Kenneth Gowland, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Ezra Groskin, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Elicia Keebler, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Kristen Johnson, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Gurudev Khalsa, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Janny Kim, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Kyle Konis, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Brendan Lee, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Andrew Moddrell, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Liat Muller, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Cynthia Myntti, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Jessica Niles DeHoff, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Sarah Rubinstein, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Charles Sevin, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Adam Sokol, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Esin Yurekli, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Damian Zunino, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Bradley Walters, 2004 (Box 3)
    - Oliver Pelle, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Exhibit Signage, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Advanced studio work - animations, 2004; 2005-A-023.0001; 1 (Box 4)
    - Use copy, optical disk (DVD) (Box 4U)
  - Advanced studio work - documentary films, 2004; 2005-A-023.0002; 1 (Box 5)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 5U)
  - Agrawal, Kanu, "Media Portraits of Ahmedabad", 2004; 2005-A-023.0003; 1 (Box 6)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 6U)
  - Arch 862b, digital video synthesis coursework, Carol Scully with Na Wei", 2004 Spring; 2005-A-023.0004; 1 (Box 8)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 7U)
- Materials relating to the Zoo Collaborative project in architecture at the School of Fine Arts, 1951-1952; Accession 2005-A-041
  - Materials relating to the Zoo Collaborative project in architecture at the School of Fine Arts, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
- Student work from M.Arch I and M.Arch II degree programs [computer files], 2003; Accession 2005-A-065 (Box 1–5)
  - Student work from M.Arch I and M.Arch II degree programs, 2003; 212 computer files (PDF, PPT, DOC, JPEG)
- Student work from M.Arch I and M.Arch II degree programs [computer files], 2004; Accession 2005-A-066 (Box 1)
  Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software
  - Bidegain, Emily-Digital Portfolio, 2004; 27
  - Campa, Brian, M. Arch I, 2004; 1
  - Carraher, Erin, M. Arch II, 2004; 2 computer files (1 PDF, 1 indd)
  - Gianinni, Patrick, 2004
  - Goldsby, 2004
  - Gowland, Kenneth, M. Arch I, 2004
  - Hyland, Patrick, 2004; 34
  - Jan, Theresa-Portfolio, 2004
  - Jogan, Matthew, M. Arch II, 2004
  - Keebler, Elicia, 2004
  - Mei, Yong, M. Arch II, 2004; 45 computer files (44 JPEG, 1 db)
  - Myntti, Cynthia, 2004; 28
  - Niles, Jessica, M. Arch I, 2004
  - Riordan, Christopher, 2004
  - Rosenblum, Ben, 2004; 1
  - Smith, Clint, 2004; 23
  - Smith, Talmadge, 2004; 1
  - Sobotka, Gregory-Portfolio, 2004; 1
  - Stone, Jeffrey, 2004; 47 computer files (TIFF)
  - Wei, Na, 2004; 36 computer files (30 JPEG, 6 db)
  - Yurekli, Esin, 2004
  - Yang, Yang, 2004; 49 computer files (JPEG)
- Masters thesis presentation of William S. Huff (M. Arch., 1952), Accession 2005-A-094
  - Masters Thesis presentation of William S. Huff (M. Arch., 1952) (Box 1)
- Digital images of the Yale Building Project exhibit [computer files], 2004; Accession 2005-A-100 (Box 1)
  - Digital images of the Yale Building Project exhibit, 2004; 18 computer files (TIFF)
- Student architectural model of William S. Huff (M. Arch., 1952), Accession 2005-A-105
  - Student architectural model of William S. Huff (M. Arch., 1952) (Box 1)
- Photographs of graduate student work from the architecture program, 1945-1958; Accession 2005-A-112
  - 1945: Philip C. Lin -- A Bus Station for New Haven Perspective (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1946
    - Lloyd Flood -- Baptist Church, Stratford, CT
      - 4.1 Plans (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 4.2 Elevations and section (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 4.3 Elevations and details (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 4.4 Perspective: Interior (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - A. E. De Salvo -- Students Room Plan (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - William Garwood -- Elementary School
      - Section and construction detail (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Interior perspective (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Isometric view, section and basement (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Elevations (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Plan (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Plot plan (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Victor F. Christ Janer -- Hamden Hall Gym
      - Perspective, elevations (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Plan, elevation (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - J. A. Kingsland -- RR Station
      - Plan, section and elevations (w/ duplicate) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Baard H. Omejer -- Furniture
      - A wall shelf (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1947
    - Lees S. Brown -- Gatekeepers Apartment
      - 4.1 Plans (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 4.3 Interior Isometric (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ralph H. Comey Jr. -- Gatekeepers Apartment
      - 5.2 Plan (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Edward Lloyd Flood -- Avenue of the Americas: Mexican Building
      - 12.3 Street Level Plan (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 12.4 First floor plan (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 12.5 Parking Layout (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 12.6 Roof level from birdseye (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 12.8 Elevation: 45th St. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 12.9 Elevation: 46th St. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 12.10 Perspective (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 12.11 Plan (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 12.12 Section and windows (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1948
    - Ralph Comey -- Cheshire Elementary School
      - 4.2 Plan (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 4.3 Final solution: plans and elevations (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 4.4 Final solution: section and classroom plan (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Ralph Comey -- Row House
      - 6.1 Plot plan (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 6.2 Plan (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 6.3 Section and elevation (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 6.4 Construction detail (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 6.5 Interior perspective (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 6.6 Exterior perspective (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - John R. McDonald -- Berkeley Divinity Chapel
      - 6.2 Perspectives (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John R. McDonald -- Suburban Residence
      - 6.1 Plot plan (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 6.2 Residence plan (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 6.3 Residence plan #2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 6.5 Elevations: SE and SW (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - 6.6 Framing Isometric (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1949
    - E. Chamberlain & Nancy Pan -- Med. School Dorm
      - 6.1 Plot plan (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 6.3 Basement plan (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 6.4 Bedroom plans (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 6.5 Model (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 6.6 Model (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Collab (Team #16) -- Center for Unesco
      - 4.3 Mural (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 4.4 Mural Detail (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A. E. De Salvo and E. A. King -- Med. School Dorm
      - 4.1 Plans and sections (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 4.2 Perspective and elevation (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 4.3 Model (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 4.4 Model: Site (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - William Guy Garwood -- A Small House for Hawaii
      - 8.1 Area Plan (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 8.2 Entry Elevation (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 8.3 Approach Elevation (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 8.4 Garden Elevation (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 8.5 Underpining System (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 8.6 Arial View (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 8.7 View with roof (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 8.8 View of model (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Paul Lochart & Karl Treffinger -- Naval Air Station
      - 1.1 Plans and perspective (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Peter Millard -- Weekend House
      - 2.1 Plan (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - 2.2 Perspective of exterior (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Nancy Yung-Chiu Pan -- A Chinese House for Nanking
      - 2.1 Model: roof on (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 2.2 Model: roof off (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Hamilton Smith -- Sub-Dept. Store
      - 4.1 Perspective (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 4.2 Plot, plan and section (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 4.3 Plans, parking and main (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 4.4 Plans; 2nd, roof and elevations (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - E. W. Winter -- House for a Collector of Oriental Art
      - 6.1 Model (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 6.2 Model (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 6.3 Plot plan (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 6.4 Plans (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 6.5 Section (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 6.6 Perspective (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1950
    - Stanley Brundage -- Barnacle Restaurant
      - 2.1 Section, elevation and perspective (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 2.2 Plot, plan and elevation (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Irving Colburn -- Gymnasiu-Assembly Hall
      - 1.1 Perspective (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Benjamin A. Gingold -- House
      - 6.5 Perspective (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Chai Yi Jen -- Barnacle Restaurant
      - 2.1 Plans and elevation (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - 2.2 Elevations, section and perspective (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1951
    - John Bedenkapp and J. Wilder Green -- Fredericksburg
      - 3.3a Perspective view (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 3.3b Perspective view (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Duncan Buell -- House of Manor of F. L. Wright
      - 4.1 Exterior perspective (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 4.2 Perspective in detail (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 4.3 Plan (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 4.4 Section and plan of sanctum (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Warren A. Peterson -- Hospital
      - 3.1 Model (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 3.2 Main floor plan (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - 3.3 Typical floor plan (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1952
    - J. D. Erikson and J. W. Green -- A Zoo
      - 3.1 Plan (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 3.2 Perspective (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 3.3 Detail plan (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1953
    - Duncan Wray Buell -- Railroad station for New Haven, CT
      - 9.1 Title Rendering (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 9.2 View of model showing structure (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 9.3 View of model showing structure (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 9.4 General view of complete model w/ layout (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 9.5 View of complete model from diff. angle (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 9.6 Plan and working drawings (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 9.7 Gross elevation and sections (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 9.8 Ground floor plan and sections (transverse) (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - 9.9 View of model showing tetrahedronal roof (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Avery Coonley Faulkner -- Residential quarters for medical students
      - 7.1 Title page (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 7.2 Plot plan and perspective (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 7.3 Gnd floor plan and upper level plan (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 7.4 Typical living units (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 7.5 Northwest elevation and basement plan (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 7.6 View of the model (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 7.7 View of the model (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - James David Gibans -- Monastery
      - 4.1 General plan (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 4.2 Framing plan of Church (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 4.3 West and south elevations (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - 4.4 Perspective of the exterior (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - K. B Skinner
      - 7.1 Plot plan (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 7.2 Lower and banking levels (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 7.3 Plot elevations (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 7.4 Floor framing systems (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 7.5 Elevations and sections (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 7.6 Sections (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - 7.7 Interior perspective (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1954
    - Vreeland, Tim and Faulkner, Avery Coonley -- A Theatre for drama for New Haven
      - 11.1 City plan and plot (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 11.2 Parking and mechanical level plan (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 11.3 Lobby and pedestrian level plan (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 11.4 Stage level plan (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 11.5 Diagrammatic section (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 11.6 East elevation (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 11.7 South elevation (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 11.8 Structure model (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 11.9 Elevation view of complete model (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - 11.10 View of model (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1955
    - William DeCossy -- Elementary School
      - 4.1 Site plan (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 4.2 Plan (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 4.3 Perspective (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 4.4 Details (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Umberto Brandigi -- Elementary School
      - 5.1 Site plan (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 5.4 Aerial perspective (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Frank Jacobi -- Elementary School
      - 6.1 Site plan (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 6.2 Plan (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 6.3 Elevations (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 6.4 Perspective (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 6.5 Perspective (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 6.6 Perspective (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1956
    - George Alfano -- Lobster Market for Rockport
      - 6.5 Perspective (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Judith Bloom -- Construction
      - 1.1 Model (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Umberto Brandigi -- Community Theater
      - 2.1 Plans and elevations (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 2.2 Elevations (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Dean Hofe -- Construction
      - 1.1 Model (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - J. L. McGuerty
      - 1.1 Model (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Harold Van Dine -- Apartment House
      - 5.2 Plan (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 5.4 Section (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 5.5 Perspective (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - James Weber -- Lobster Market for Rockport
      - 7.1 Site plan (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 7.2 Plan and elevation (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 7.3 Details (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 7.5 Perspective (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 7.7 Perspective (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1957
    - Thomas Green -- Sprayed Concrete Construction
      - 3.1 Model (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Leo Model -- Yacht Club for NYC
      - 13.9 Interior Perspective (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - David Prescott -- Summer House
      - 3.2 Plan (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 5.4 Model (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Joaquin Rallo -- City Center for Ceuta
      - 38.38 Model (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1958
    - Giovanni Pasanella -- Apts. for Sacramento
      - 2.1 Plot plan, plans (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 2.2 Model (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Medal Winning Designs -- Date Unknown
    General
    Images, which are glued to backer boards, are listed by category, and alphabetically by creator therein. Occasionally more than one image is attached to the same backer board; in those instances, the board is filed by the name which occurs first in the list.
    - 1st Medal/Mention
      - R. Ayers -- An International Athletic Centre (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - R. Ayers -- Athletic Centre (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Charles M. Brooks -- Academia Americana (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - G. L. Cochran -- A Roadside Tea House (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - J. P. Cone -- An English Wrought Iron Gate (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - T. W. Dominick -- A Synagogue (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Scott Fitzhugh, Jr. -- An Apartment House Development (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - R. M. Hersey -- A Recreation Center (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - E. V. Johnson -- "A Recreation Center" (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - E. V. Johnson -- "A Sir Christopher Wren Steeple" (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - J. L. King -- A Synagogue (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - W. Prokosch -- New Thousand Dollar Bill (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - M. C. Robb -- Office of American Ambassador... (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - M. C. Robb -- Unknown title (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Malcolm C. Robb -- Amer. Academy in Florence (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - V. Sears -- A City Residence (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - W. K. Sturges -- A Shop Front (Emerson Prize) (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - M. O. Urbahn -- Entrance to Important Building (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - D. N. Yerkes -- "A Roadside Tea House..." (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 2nd Medal/Mention
      - G. Chapman -- A Post Office (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - A. L. Finn (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - E. V. Johnson -- A Living Room in Adobe House (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - R. H. Licht (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - E. Saarinen -- A Baroque Fountain (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Selected Mention
      - M. C. Robb -- A Planetarium (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Unknown student work (3), Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Student papers written for Robert A. M. Stern's course on "Eero Saarinen and His Times", 2005; Accession 2005-A-169
  - The Bell Laboratories, by J. Barr, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Search for Perfect Form, by A. Falley Burns, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Father's Legacy, by N. Elchert, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The John Deere Administration Building, by N. Friend, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Oslo Embassy, by T. Gharagozlou, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stuctural Fact & Structural Expression, by C. Gonzalez-Quintanilla, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kresge Auditorium, by A. Heeren, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Miller House & Shoin Architecture, by K. Henderson, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The St. Louis Arch, by A. Phillips, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - TWA Terminal, by R. Ringemann, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Campus Work of Eero Saarinen, by A. Sreshta, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The MIT Chapel, by L. Stevens, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Total Design, by M. Unger, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The London Embassy, by S. Ybarra, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "Williamsburg: resurgence" by Professor Alexander Garvin, 2005; Accession 2005-A-194
  - "Williamsburg: resurgence" by Professor Alexander Garvin, Intermediate Planning & Development Class (905b), 2005 (Box 1)
- Drawings of Donal McLaughlin, 1929-1939; Accession 2005-A-202
  - "Doorway to an Embassy Garden," Analytique (Box 1)
  - "Entrance to an Architect's Office Building, Analytique (Box 1)
  - "A $100 Blll'' Esquisse Esquisse, 1929-30 (Box 1)
  - "A Mernorlal," Paris Prize Preliminary (Box 1)
  - "A Police Station" Esq.-Esq., 1929-30 (Box 1)
  - "A Fountain" Paris Prize Preliminary (Box 1)
  - "A Subway Termrnal" Esq. Esq., 1931-32 (Box 1)
  - "A Farm Group", Esq.-Esq., 1932 (Box 1)
  - "A Monumental Band Stand" Paris Prize Preliminary (Box 1)
  - "A Crematorium" Esq. -Esq, 1932 (Box 1)
  - "A College Group" School Project (Box 1)
  - "A Chapel" School Project, 1931-32 (Box 1)
  - "An Immigration Statlon" Special Prize Program, 11382 (Box 1)
  - "Memorial to Thomas' Edison" Paris Prize Preliminary (Box 1)
  - "A Lighthouse" Paris Prize Preliminary, Class A, 1934 (Box 1)
  - "Osbourne Planetarium Thesis" detail, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Livinq Dining Room Interior Design competition for Bryant Park N.Y.C., 1939 (Box 1)
  - A Memorial To Daniel Boone (Box 1)
  - "A Fountain and Dam" Class A, 1932 (Box 2)
  - "A Fountain," Analytique (Box 2)
  - "Entrance to Egyptian Museum" Analytique (Box 3)
  - "A Memorial Museum" Class B Esquisse Esquisse, February 1930 (Box 3)
  - "An Elementary School", Class B (Box 3)
  - "A Harbor Site" (Box 3)
  - "A State Hospital for Nervous Disorder" Class Warren Prize, 1931-32 (Box 3)
  - "An Historical Museum for Bologna" School Project (Box 3)
  - "Rome Collaborative," (est.), 1934 (Box 3)
  - "A College of a University" Warren Prize (collaborated with Saarinen), 1933 (Box 3)
  - "A Georgian Music Room" Interior Design, 1934 (Box 3)
  - "A Monastery in the Rocky Mountains", Class A, 1930 (Box 4)
  - "A Stock Exchange" Columbia, Prlnceton, Yale Project (Box 4)
  - "A City Residence" (Box 4)